<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GuideMi</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="duomo_name">Duomo di Milano</string>
    <string name="duomo_address">Piazza del Duomo, Milano</string>
    <string name="duomo_desc">The Duomo, besides being an artistic monument, is a privileged place of prayer. The Cathedral is strongly linked to memory and to the Magisterium of the Bishops who have succeeded to the Throne of St. Ambrose and to the history of the millions of faithful who collect their thoughts there each year to celebrate the Sacred Mysteries.\n\nThe Cathedral is the Mother Church of the Diocese, which has a symbolic exemplary function both with regard to the life of religion in the city, and with regard to diocesan activity.  Liturgical activity is the true essence of the Cathedral: the Duomo is the heart of liturgical tradition which, referring to the figure of St. Ambrose, is an expression of the tangible form with which the apostolic tradition is deeply rooted and has developed over the centuries in the Church of Milan.  In the Duomo, daily liturgical worship is practiced in many different forms: not only celebrations of the Eucharist, but also, because of the constant presence of the Metropolitan Chapter, the Liturgy of the Hours, as preparation for and prolongation of the Eucharist.\n\nParticular attention is paid to Eucharistic Adoration, the Liturgy of the Word, celebration of the Sacrament of Reconciliation and to the most genuine and sincere forms of “popular piety”, such as reciting of the Rosary and, during Lent, the practice of the Stations of the Cross. Liturgical worship by the faithful is the essence of the Cathedral which, in all of its expressions, above all through the countless works of art that it has preserved for centuries, is required to live and give testimony in the very heart of the city to faithfulness to Christ\'s Gospel. </string>
    <string name="sforza_name">Castle Sforzesco</string>
    <string name="sforza_address">Piazza Castello, Milano</string>
    <string name="sforza_desc">The Castle, one of the most representative and popular monuments in Milan, has undergone over the centuries various and complex transformations; it has been defence fortress, military barracks, private residence and centre of cultural institutions and museums.\n\nBecause of its evident defensive structure, it underwent sieges, demolitions and reconstructions of some parts of it during French, Spanish and Austrian domination.\n\nThe events of the Castle unfold in the city’s wide window of history, beginning with the original nucleus of the castle, named Porta Giovia, dating back to 1358-1368  during Galeazzo II Visconti’s period who used the Castle as his residence while he stayed in Milan, but mostly used it as a military base.
The Castle became Filippo Maria Visconti’s permanent residence, continuing with the consolidation and construction of a real fortress. Later, it was mainly Francesco Sforza who, as  ruler of Milan in 1450, gave particular impetus to the reconstruction of the building  which had been seriously damaged between 1447 and 1450.\n\nToday the Castle hosts many Civic Museums; in fact, since 1896 it has hosted one of the vastest artistic collections in the city, mainly in the Museo d’Arte Antica (Museum of Ancient Art).\n\n 
There is also the Pinacoteca (Picture Gallery), Raccolta di Mobili (Furniture Collection), with pieces from the 15th to the 19th century; the Rocchetta, where one can admire the Museo delle Arti Decorative ((Museum of Decorative Arts), with its extremely vast collection of ceramics; the Oreficerie (Goldsmiths); one of the largest collection of musical instruments in Europe; the Arazzi Trivulzio (Trivulzio Tapestries); the Armeria (Armoury); the Museo della Preistoria e Protostoria (the Museum of Prehistory and Protohistory); the Museo Egizio (Egyptian Museum) and the Sale Viscontee,  rooms for temporary exhibitions. Finally, many important archives and libraries are located in the Castle: Biblioteca d’Arte (Library of Art), the Archivio Storico (Historic Archive), the Biblioteca Trivulziana (Trivulziana Library), the Biblioteca Archeologica e Numismatica (Archaeological and Numismatics Library), C.A.S.V.A. (Centre for Advanced Study in Visual Arts), Raccolta delle Stampe “Achille Bertarelli” (“Achille Bertarelli” Print Collection), Archivio Fotografico (Photographic Archive) and the Raccolta Vinciana (Vinciana Collection).\n\n
The last masterpiece of Michelangelo, the Pietà Rondanini, can be found in the Museo della Pietà Rondanini, opened in 2015 in the Spanish hospital inside the Castle and dedicated exclusively to the sculpture.</string>
    <string name="galleria_name">Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II</string>
    <string name="galleria_address">Piazza del Duomo, Milano</string>
    <string name="galleria_desc">The Galleria, a place of transit for busy managers or a stop for enchanted and curious tourists, expresses the various faces of the city through its many facets.\n\nAs soon as it was finished, the Galleria became immediately famous for its large size, extraordinary for the time and sign of a new era.\n\nThe 20th century is synonymous with modernity and progress. It’s an intricate and complex historical period that saw technical accelerations, engineering-industrial products, and, in general, the rise of the work of the human genius.\n\nThe great spaces of the Galleria foresaw a reality that has its distinguishing mark in the sense of movement. We can’t forget here, in the artistic field, a masterpiece such as “Riot in the Gallery” (Rissa in Galleria) by Boccioni, that represents reality in an innovative way, projected into a dynamic future. Cars, trams, work in factories: everything was changing the rhythm of the city and the people’s idea on everyday life.\n\n
Considered one of the sites of Milanese luxury shopping, along with Via Montenapoleone and Via della Spiga, it hosts many prestigious labels and brand shops, famous cafés and restaurants, as well as Feltrinelli Records, one of the largest megastores in Italy.\n\nTaking that classic wander through the Galleria, the very heart of the city, as visitors have done for many years, still creates that wonderful sensation. Entering the Galleria, the corridor between Duomo and La Scala Theatre, its magnificent arch welcomes you and hints at the Milanese spectacle that lies within. The original idea of the designers was to create a porticoed street that would function as a showcase and offer somewhere to take a pleasant stroll, enjoy an aperitif or have dinner after the opera.\n\nToday it can still be considered the “parlour” of the city, a place where you relax and enjoy a coffee at the bar Camparino, let yourself be enchanted by the cute hats of Borsalino and the collections of Prada and Louis Vuitton, or stop for an aperitif at Savini.\n\n
If you wish to return to Milan, the tradition suggests that you have a spin with your heel on the mosaic bulls “attributes” that make up the pavement of the Galleria’s splendid central octagon. Once a gesture to ward off evil, it has become part of the Milanese tradition and has such a following that a deep hole has formed in the pavement.\n\nYou will surely enjoy visiting the Galleria, it will also feel like turning the clock back in time: for the construction, which started in 1865 (by Giuseppe Mengoni) were used mainly iron and glass as for the Parisian train stations, a well-advanced technique in those days.\n\nOn occasion, the Galleria also offers shelter to its guests from sudden rain or from the hot sun, welcoming them in its extraordinary and elegant atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="scala_name">Teatro alla Scala</string>
    <string name="scala_address">Via Filodrammatici, 2, Milano</string>
    <string name="scala_desc">The Teatro alla Scala was built as a replacement of the old Teatro Ducale in 1776 by order of the empress Maria Theresa of Austria, and was inaugurated in 1778 with Antonio Salieri’s Europa riconosciuta. It owes its name to the place where it was built by the neoclassical architect Giuseppe Piermarini: the church of Santa Maria alla Scala.\n\nAssigned place to melodrama, world famous artists performed at the Scala such as Rossini, Donizetti, Bellini and Verdi.\n\nThe theatre was rebuilt after the bombing in 1943 and inaugurated a second time in 1946 with a concert conducted by artist director Arturo Toscanini.\n\nSince 1951, as for artistic director Victor De Sabata’s wish, the opening night takes place on the 7th of December,  the feast of St Ambrose, patron saint of Milan. This helps to give extra symbolic meaning to the première.\n\n
Famous opera singers such as Maria Callas, Renata Tebaldi, Giulietta Simionato, Mirella Freni, Mario Del Monaco, Giuseppe Di Stefano, Luciano Pavarotti, Placido Domingo; film directors Luchino Visconti, Franco Zeffirelli, Luca Ronconi; well-known choreographers and dancers Leonide Massine, George Balanchine, Rudolf Nureyev, Carla Fracci, Luciana Savignano among others performed at the Scala.\n\nWith this musical offering and thanks to the rebuilding and modernisation of the scenic machinery undertaken between 2002 and 2004, La Scala is on a level with the greatest theatres of Europe and the world since the end of WWII.\n\nOn the 7th of December 2004 Riccardo Muti inaugurated the restored theatre playing Europa Riconosciuta by Salieri, as for the very first premiere in 1778.</string>
    <string name="arco_name">Arco della Pace</string>
    <string name="arco_address">Piazza Sempione, Milano</string>
    <string name="arco_desc">The Arco della Pace (Arch of Peace), one of the most interesting example of neoclassical architecture, characterizes the surrounding area.\n\nLuigi Cagnola began its construction in 1807 when the city was under Napoleonic rule. It is located at the centre of the large square, Piazza Sempione. It was interrupted after Napoleon’s defeat at Waterloo, and then completed by Francis I of Austria who dedicated it to Peace.\n\nOn the face of the monument, there are embodiments of the rivers of Lombardy and Veneto: the rivers Po, Ticino, Adda and Tagliamento.\n\nThe monument is built from Baveno granite, clad in marble from Creola d’Òssola. At the top there is a superb statuary group in bronze, the “Chariot of Peace” drawn by six horses, and four “Victorias on horseback”.\n\n
    In his book “A Moveable Feast”, Ernest Hemingway reports the erroneous conviction that the Arco della Pace is aligned with the Arc de Triomphe at the Carousel and the Arc du Triomphe at the Étoile, both in Paris.\n\nOriginally the enormous group consisting of the chariot and six horses faced France, but after the fall of Napoleon and the advent of the Austrian domination in Milan, the chariot was turned around to face the city centre.</string>
    <string name="aulenti_name">Piazza Gae Aulenti</string>
    <string name="aulenti_address">Piazza Gae Aulenti, Milano</string>
    <string name="aulenti_desc">If Piazza Duomo is the historic heart of Milan then Piazza Gae Aulenti represents the new face of the city, the symbol of a metropolis that is changing and looking ahead to the future.\n\nThe Piazza sits at the heart of the Porta Nuova development, the urban renovation of the Garibaldi, Isola and Varesine districts: a circular piazza of about 80 mts in diameter with a surface area of ​​2,300 m2, it is raised 10 mts above ground with three intermediate levels (underground station, parking, retail).\n\nDesigned by the Argentine architect Cesar Pelli as a stunning new gateway to Milan, it was inaugurated on December 8th, 2012 and dedicated to the architect and designer Gae Aulenti. A significant accolade to a woman who, thanks to her extraordinary creative talent, managed to distinguish herself in times, and in a profession, that was predominantly male.\n\n
Paved with slate, it is surrounded by two levels of canopies in iron, wood and glass built in accordance with the principles of eco-sustainability; it is covered with solar panels that provide power for the three adjacent towers. The piazza is enhanced by three circular infinity fountains surrounded by a 105 metre flowing circle of curved seating in stone grit and porticoes that adorn the underlying walkways and shop windows.</string>
    <string name="grazie_name">Santa Maria delle Grazie</string>
    <string name="grazie_address">Piazza di Santa Maria delle Grazie, Milano</string>
    <string name="grazie_desc">The Church of Santa Maria delle Grazie, situated in the heart of Milan, is an outstanding work of architecture, and an emblem within the Catholic tradition. Santa Maria delle Grazie is perhaps even more famous for its indissoluable connection to Leonardo Da Vinci\'s fresco of “The Last Supper,” preserved inside its refectory (dining hall).\n\nThe Church is one of Renaissance art\'s most important testimonies and a shining symbol of creative human genius -  thus it became a UNESCO World Heritage List in 1980.\n\nOften a crossroads for crucial political, social and economic events, Milan has long held an important role in the Italian Peninsula’s history. In 1460, Count Gaspare Vimercati, commander of Francesco Sforza’s militias, gave the Dominican Order a chapel bearing a frescoed depiction of the Madonna delle Grazie until the Dominicans were able to build their own church and monastery.
    Construction began in 1463, with Guiniforte Solari in charge of planning and direction; the monastery was completed in 1469, the church in 1482. Ludovico the Moor (Sforza) later modified it so that it could serve as mausoleum for his family.\n\nWith Bramante at the helm of these changes, the structure was enlarged according to his unique genius: the addition of large, semi-circular apses, a majestic cupola with a border of colonnades, a gorgeous cloister and, finally, the refectory.</string>
    <string name="cimitero_name">Monumental Cemetery</string>
    <string name="cimitero_address">Piazzale Cimitero Monumentale, Milano</string>
    <string name="cimitero_desc">The Monumental Cemetery, more than just a simple cemetery, is an extraordinary outdoor museum. It is as if some of the great sculptors of the 1900s were called together to elaborate and reflect on a particularly demanding theme, to be precise, death.\n\nJust observing it from the outside, this place strikes you for its grand dimensions, a space of 250 thousand metres squared, a sort of grand oasis of peace, silence and tranquillity. And those who imagine this cemetery as an especially sad place are mistaken. In reality, it presents itself as a pleasant place to visit, filled with inscriptions that invite you to remember those who have gone before, rich with information and accompanied by interesting artistic detail.\n\nThe cemetery is comprised of three distinct zones: the central one hosts the tombs of catholic families and persons, that to the right facing the facade, is reserved for Jewish persons, while the left is dedicated to non-Catholics.\n\n
From an architectural perspective, you can catch a glimpse of both Romanic and Gothic traces. Along the principal paths, in order to help visitors, there are some maps that bear the indications of the most interesting monuments and among these the Famedio (Memorial Chapel) is indicated. It is a voluminous construction made of bricks and marble in Neo-medieval style where, amongst other personages, Alessandro Manzoni is buried.\n\nBut the surprises don’t finish here. In a secondary path on the left, you reach the tomb of the celebrated Campari family, famous for the noted aperitif brand, who chose to build a slightly larger than life-size Last Supper in bronze. It is signed by Giannino Castiglioni who created it in 1935.\n\nThose wishing to admire work of the great sculptor Medardo Rosso, should make their way to monument number 325 where one can find the figure of Filippo Filippi, musical critic and composer who was closely connected with the Milanese Scapigliatura.\n\n
The tomb of Arturo Toscanini, another monument not to be missed, is the work of sculptor Leonardo Bistolfi. It strikes you for its delicacy and its dramatic nature as it alludes to little Giorgio, his son that was prematurely lost, and to his parents’ desperation who can be seen embracing each other. On the front of the monument there is a boat which portrays the voyage of the little boy\'s remains returning from New York, like a metaphor representing the moment of passing.</string>
    <string name="sansiro_name">San Siro Stadium</string>
    <string name="sansiro_address">Piazzale Angelo Moratti, Milano</string>
    <string name="sansiro_desc">In 1925, President of A.C. Milan Piero Pirelli called for the construction of a soccer stadium near the Hippodrome for Trotting Races.\n\nThe structure, as designed by the engineer Alberto Cugini and the architect Ulisse Stacchini, is made up of four back straight bleachers, one of which is partially covered, and can contain up to 35,000 spectators.\n\nAfter buying the stadium, the City of Milan started a first round of renovations in 1935 that led to the construction of four connecting curves between the bleachers, with an increase in the capacity of the two front ones. The renovations, supervised by the engineer Bertera and architect Perlasca, provided the people of Milan a stadium with 55.000 seats.\n\nThe Stadium was built to host mainly Milan\’s matches of A.C. Milan, but in 1947-1948 it became the home of Inter as well.\n\nThe second round of renovations, designed by the engineer Ferruccio Calzolari and the architect Armando Ronca, drastically altered the appearance of the stadium in 1955: a supporting structure was built ​​for a second level of bleachers that stood over and partly covered the old ones. The total capacity increased to 100,000 seats; later, because of safety measures, it was reduced to 85,000, divided between seating (about 60,000) and standing.\n\n
The architectural image of the stadium was modernized by the helicoal ramps that allow access to the second level. The illumination system that continues to allow night matches was implemented in 1957, with the electric scoreboard added ten years after that.\n\nIn 1980, this “Temple of Soccer” was named “Giuseppe Meazza” to honor the unforgettable Milanese player who played both for Inter and AC Milan and was a two-time World Champion with the Italian national team.\n\nIn 1990, on the occasion of the World Cup, the City of Milan decided to work on a deep renovation of the stadium, discarding the idea of building a new structure.</string>
    <string name="bosco_name">Bosco Verticale</string>
    <string name="bosco_address">Via De Castillia, Milano</string>
    <string name="bosco_desc">Vertical Forest is a model for a sustainable residential building, a project for metropolitan reforestation contributing to the regeneration of the environment and urban biodiversity without the implication of expanding the city upon the territory. It is a model of vertical densification of nature within the city that operates in relation to policies for reforestation and naturalization of large urban and metropolitan borders. The first example of the Vertical Forest consisting of two residential towers of 110 and 76 m height, was realized in the centre of Milan, on the edge of the Isola neighborhood, hosting 900 trees (each measuring 3, 6 or 9 meters) and over 20,000 plants from a wide range of shrubs and floral plants distributed according to the sun exposure of the facade. On flat land, each Vertical Forest equals, in amount of trees, an area of 7,000 sq.m  of forest. In terms of urban densification it is the equivalent of an area of a single family dwelling of nearly 75,000 sq.m. The vegetal system of the Vertical Forest contributes to the construction of a microclimate, produces humidity, absorbs CO2 and dust particles and produces oxygen.</string>
    <string name="ribot_name">Ristorante Ribot</string>
    <string name="ribot_address">Via Cremosano 41, Milano</string>
    <string name="ribot_desc">The ancient influence of favouring fresh herbs over their dried counterparts is still evident in Tuscan cuisine. Simple and earthy, Ribot celebrates the seasons with fresh vegetable dishes, wonderful bread-based soups, and meats perfumed with sage, rosemary and thyme. Here they serve one of the best fiorentinas (steaks) in town, though my favourite dish is maccheroncini alla montalcino (pasta with a marinated meat sauce). With its great outdoor location and amazing gourmet appetizers buffet, Ribot is a must in summer. The chocolate dipping fruit dessert is a classic!</string>
    <string name="rebelot_name">Rebelot del Pont</string>
    <string name="rebelot_address">Ripa di Porta Ticinese, 55, Milano</string>
    <string name="rebelot_desc">If there’s one Milan restaurant that’s as inventive as the néo-bistrots that have taken Paris by storm, it’s Rebelot. It’s the most exciting place to dine in Milan, hands down. Chef Mauricio Zillo’s whimsical menu of eight to ten small plates changes quite regularly, having featured 200 dishes last year alone. Don’t let straightforward menu descriptions such as “roasted octopus and lentils” fool you; the beautifully executed preparations are striking, elegant and thoughtful. You’d fare well to let Mauricio decide dinner for you by opting for the gastronomic menu — three courses costs €26; four, €36; and five, €48. Couple your repast with one of mixologist Oscar Quagliarini’s clever libations.</string>
    <string name="ratana_name">Ratanà</string>
    <string name="ratana_address">Via Gaetano de Castillia 28, Milano</string>
    <string name="ratana_desc">The beautiful 19th-century industrial building that houses Ratanà is, not unlike the old man’s house in the movie Up, the only remaining historical construction in a neighborhood razed to the ground and completely rebuilt to become the futuristic Isola-Garibaldi project. The name of the restaurant is itself a tribute to the old times: Ratanà was the nickname of a half-priest, half-healer who cured the poor people of the quarter more than 100 years ago. Born and bred Milanese chef Cesare Battisti offers a modern take on Lombardy’s traditional recipes. While his saffron risotto is arguably the best the city has to offer, it’s his love for oft-neglected freshwater fish that has singlehandedly started a mini-revolution in the city.</string>
    <string name="drymilano_name">Dry Milano</string>
    <string name="drymilano_address">Via Solferino 33, Milano</string>
    <string name="drymilano_desc">Even in Italy, finding really good pizza is hard. Despite what Neapolitans would like you to believe, it’s not about having the perfect water. The number-one rule? The dough — not the toppings — is what pizza is all about, and Dry Milano’s delicate, flavorful dough is exactly what makes its pizza stand out. Go for a “less is more” approach and try the marinara, with just tomato sauce. By the way, pizza is just half of what makes this sleek, industrial-chic venue popular: Dry serves outstanding Prohibition-era cocktails. Call ahead or be prepared to wait in a line of beautiful Milanese. The people-watching will keep you busy.</string>
    <string name="joia_name">Joia</string>
    <string name="joia_address">Via Panfilo Castaldi 18, Milano</string>
    <string name="joia_desc">When Joia first opened 25 years ago, the idea of a gourmet vegetarian restaurant sounded like pure folly. Today, Joia is still going strong — it boasts a Michelin star — and recently started leaning toward vegan cuisine. The chef, Pietro Leemann, believes in a “cooking as medicine” philosophy, with some Buddhist wisdom thrown in the mix. Expect the occasional quirky twist: The dessert “gong,” for instance, is meant to involve all senses, so to make sure that your hearing takes part in the fun along with your tasting buds, your server rings a gong before you start eating.</string>
    <string name="cracco_name">Ristorante Cracco</string>
    <string name="cracco_address">Via Victor Hugo 4, Milano</string>
    <string name="cracco_desc">Über-talented chef Carlo Cracco catapulted to TV stardom when he became one of the judges on the Italian edition of the popular talent show MasterChef. After that, scoring a reservation in his eponymous Michelin two-starred restaurant has become no small feat, despite the fact that the intellectual, personal cuisine of the chef is not a crowd-pleaser per se: His love for offal and his penchant for pure, unsubtle flavors have always made him somewhat of a chefs’ chef.</string>
    <string name="posto_name">Un Posto a Milano</string>
    <string name="posto_address">Via Privata Cuccagna 2, Milano</string>
    <string name="posto_desc">Visiting Milan today, it’s difficult to imagine that until a century ago, parts of the city now almost central were considered “countryside.” Yet Cascina Cuccagna, an 18th-century farmhouse, offers such proof. Three years ago, following an extensive renovation, the Cascina reopened to the public with one of the most interesting restaurants in town, Un Posto a Milano — literally, “a place in Milan” (quite the understatement). Un Posto a Milano serves unpretentious farm-to-table food, always fresh and delicious, with a lot of vegetarian options and a focus on local ingredients. As soon as the weather warms up, the beautiful courtyard with its vegetable garden becomes one of the most frequented places in town.</string>
    <string name="mangiari_name">Mangiari di Strada</string>
    <string name="mangiari_address">Via Lorenteggio 269, Milano</string>
    <string name="mangiari_desc">Getting here is certainly not easy, but a street-food paradise awaits you following the onerous trek to the dismal Milan outskirts. Take your pick from chef Giuseppe Zen’s glorious array of street-food specialties that span all of Italy, such as panino con lampredotto (a cow’s fourth stomach), native to Tuscany, fried Neapolitan pizza, and jota, a bean-and-sauerkraut soup typical of Trieste. Because it’s open for lunch only, it’s best to arrive early, as seats can be few and far between, particularly during the cooler months, when the outdoor garden is closed.</string>
    <string name="berbere_name">Berberè</string>
    <string name="berbere_address">Via Sebenico 21, Milano</string>
    <string name="berbere_desc">Craft pizzas and craft beers is what Bolognese brothers Matteo and Salvatore promise you at this fantastically good pizzeria housed in an atmospheric 1950s cooperative. Everything from the Black Elk flour (they use variations of spelt, enkir and kamut which give a lighter finish than wheat) to the Ponteré mozzarella, the Torre Guaceto tomatoes and Puglian fiordilatte is sourced obsessively for the optimum flavour punch. Book ahead.</string>
    <string name="brisa_name">Ristorante La Brisa</string>
    <string name="brisa_address">Via Brisa 15, Milano</string>
    <string name="brisa_desc">Discreet, elegant and exquisitely romantic. Push open the screened door and the maître d\' will guide you to a table beneath centuries-old linden trees in a secluded courtyard, where ivy climbs the walls and pink hydrangeas bob in the breeze. Chef Antonio Facciolo\'s seasonal menus are similarly elegant, his signature dish a mouthwatering roast pork in a myrtle-berry drizzle.</string>
    <string name="pinacoteca_brera_name">Pinacoteca di Brera</string>
    <string name="pinacoteca_brera_address">Via Brera, 28, Milano</string>
    <string name="pinacoteca_brera_desc">The Brera Gallery was officially established in 1809, even though a first heterogeneous collection with educational purpose existed already from 1776 – and then increased in the following years – alongside the Accademia di Belle Arti, requested by Mary Therese of Austria to offer the students the opportunity to study lofty masterpieces of art close up.\n\nBrera become a museum to host the most important works of art from all of the areas conquered by the French armies. So unlike other important museums in Italy such as the Uffizi, Brera did not start out life as the private collection of a prince or nobleman but as the product of a deliberate policy decision.\n\nPaintings confiscated from churches and convents throughout Lombardy with the religious orders’ dissolution began to pour into the museum in the early years of the 19th century, soon to be joined by artworks of similar provenance from other areas of the Kingdom of Italy. This explains why the collection comprises chiefly religious works, many of them large altarpieces, and accounts for Brera’s special aura on which later acquisitions have had only a minor impact.</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="more">More info</string>
    <string name="webpage">Webpage</string>
    <string name="audio">Audio Guide</string>
    <string name="map">Map</string>
    <string name="sights">Sights</string>
    <string name="restaurants">To eat</string>
    <string name="museums">Museums</string>
    <string name="duomo_url">http://www.duomomilano.it</string>
    <string name="sforza_url">https://www.milanocastello.it/</string>
    <string name="galleria_url">http://www.ingalleria.com</string>
    <string name="scala_url">http://www.teatroallascala.org/en/index.html</string>
    <string name="arco_url">http://www.turismo.milano.it/wps/portal/tur/en/arteecultura/architetturaemonumenti/monumenti/Arco_Pace</string>
    <string name="aulenti_url">http://www.turismo.milano.it/wps/portal/tur/en/arteecultura/architetturaemonumenti/grattacieliearchitetturamoderna/PIAZZA_GAE_AULENTI</string>
    <string name="grazie_url">https://legraziemilano.it/</string>
    <string name="cimitero_url">http://www.comune.milano.it/wps/portal/ist/it/vivicitta/luoghicultura/Musei_Spazi_espositivi/cimitero_monumentale</string>
    <string name="sansiro_url">http://www.sansiro.net</string>
    <string name="bosco_url">https://www.stefanoboeriarchitetti.net/en/portfolios/bosco-verticale/</string>
    <string name="ribot_url">http://www.ribotmilano.it/</string>
    <string name="rebelot_url">https://www.rebelotnavigli.com/</string>
    <string name="ratana_url">http://ratana.it/</string>
    <string name="drymilano_url">http://www.drymilano.it/</string>
    <string name="joia_url">http://www.joia.it/</string>
    <string name="cracco_url">http://www.ristorantecracco.it/</string>v
    <string name="posto_url">http://unpostoamilano.it/index_eng.php</string>
    <string name="mangiari_url">http://mangiaridistrada.com/?lang=en</string>
    <string name="berbere_url">http://www.berberepizza.it/</string>
    <string name="brisa_url">http://www.ristorantelabrisa.it/</string>
    <string name="pinacoteca_brera_url">http://pinacotecabrera.org/en/</string>
    <string name="museo_duomo_url">http://museo.duomomilano.it/en/</string>
    <string name="museo_duomo_name">Museo del Duomo</string>
    <string name="museo_duomo_address">Piazza del Duomo, 12, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_duomo_desc">The Cathedral Museum was opened in 1953 by the art critic Ugo Nebbia, but the idea took shape in the last quarter of the nineteenth century, when it became necessary to find a way of keeping together and preserving the huge amount of material connected with the history and construction of the Cathedral.\n\nIn 1948 the Fabbrica del Duomo obtained the concession from the State Property Department for nine rooms located on the ground floor of the oldest wing of Palazzo Reale, formerly the residence of the Visconti and Sforza families, renovated by the architect Piermarini in the second half of the eighteenth century.\n\nAt last suitable premises were available to house and exhibit the works to be preserved, which had significantly increased in number after the damage caused by the bombing in the Second World War.
The deterioration of many works of art, caused by atmospheric pollution, and the influx of further material from the Fabbrica storerooms and the Cathedral vestries soon made a larger exhibition area necessary.\n\nIn the Sixties the Museum was enlarged and re-opened with the addition of a further ten rooms - some of which were of great architectural prestige - by concession of Milan City Council, completely re-fitted and re-organised by the architect Ernesto Brivio on the basis of a historical-chronological project. In 2013 the Museum re-opened after a long period of renovation and re-fitting under a project by the architect Guido Canali.</string>
    <string name="museo_novecento_url">http://www.museodelnovecento.org/en/</string>
    <string name="museo_novecento_name">Museo del Novecento</string>
    <string name="museo_novecento_address">Via Guglielmo Marconi, 1, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_novecento_desc">The Museo del Novecento, located inside the Palazzo dell’Arengario in Piazza del Duomo, hosts a collection of over four thousand works that catalyze the development of 20th century Italian art.\n\nThe Museo del Novecento was established on 6 December 2010 with the goal of spreading knowledge of 20th century art and offering a more comprehensive insight into the collections that the city of Milan has inherited over time. Beside its core exhibition activity, the Museum is active in the conservation, investigation and promotion of 20th century Italian cultural and artistic heritage with the final aim of reaching an ever wider audience.\n\nWith an eye toward the city, the Museo del Novecento develops around multiple locations. The Permanent Collection follows a chronological path where collective exhibitions alternate with solo art shows. The grand spiral staircase inside the building welcomes visitors and introduces them to the visit of the Museum with the Il Quarto Stato (The Fourth Estate) by Pellizza da Volpedo. The bookshop and the restaurant are the Museum’s meeting places. The Neon by Lucio Fontana represents a final embrace to the city. Reflecting Milan’s feverish cultural dynamism, the Permanent Collection is essentially the story of several private collections that have been brought together thanks to the generosity and passion for art of many private collectors. Since its inception, the collection has been augmented by major gifts from artists, collectors and philanthropists who play an active role in the growth of the Museum’s heritage, which today reflects the rich trajectory of art from the early 20th century through the present.\n\n
    An outstanding example of architecture and, today, an impressive installation communicating directly with the city, since 2010 the Palazzo dell’Arengario has accommodated the Museo del Novecento. This landmark building, designed by Griffini, Magistretti, Muzio, and Portaluppi, was renovated by the Rota Group to host a richly layered collection of 20th century Italian art.\n\nThe transformation of the Palazzo dell’Arengario was dictated by the need to organize the composition of Milan’s Civiche Raccolte d’Arte (Municipal Art Collections) around two distinct poles. While the historic premises of Villa Reale were meant to host collections dating from the 19th century, the Palazzo dell’Arengario was singled out for the exhibits of 20th century artwork. The latter was particularly meaningful for the harmony existing between its architecture and the collection it was meant to display.\n\nThis project enabled to best exploit the interior premises, while turning the building into one of the major cultural places in Milan. The grand spiral staircase inside the building is probably the most impressive architectural feature of the Museum: a functional element that connects several levels, from the subway up to the panoramic terrace overlooking the Duomo.</string>
    <string name="museo_castello_url">https://www.milanocastello.it/</string>
    <string name="museo_castello_name">Musei del Castello Sforzesco</string>
    <string name="museo_castello_address">Piazza Castello, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_castello_desc">The castle hosts actually the following museums:\n\nPinacoteca del Castello Sforzesco\n\nMuseo della Preistoria\n\nMuseo egizio\n\nMuseo d\'arte antica\n\nMuseo degli strumenti musicali\n\n
Museo del Mobile\n\nRaccolte d\'Arte Applicata\n\nRaccolte Extraeuropee\n\nRivellino del Santo Spirito (escursione tra i tetti e i passaggi coperti sulla mura esterne del castello)\n\nArchivio Storico Civico e Biblioteca Trivulziana\n\n
Biblioteca d\'Arte del Castello Sforzesco\n\nCivica raccolta delle stampe Achille Bertarelli\n\nLibreria del Castello</string>
    <string name="museo_armani_url">https://www.armanisilos.com/en_WW/</string>
    <string name="museo_armani_name">Museo Armani/Silos</string>
    <string name="museo_armani_address">Via Bergognone, 40, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_armani_desc">At the Armani/Silos, Giorgio Armani shows us a glimpse of his world: the dream of a measured, timeless aesthetic approach which has changed not only our way of dressing, but also and above all our way of thinking.\n\nBuilt in 1950 for storing cereals, today this ample 4,500 square-metre space spread over four floors houses a unique selection of the fashion designer’s creations, divided into themes that tell the story behind their aesthetics and their history.\n\n
Guided tours last for approximately one hour and are available for purchase exclusively through the official channels of Armani/Silos.</string>
    <string name="museo_scienza_url">http://www.museoscienza.org/</string>
    <string name="museo_scienza_name">Museo Nazionale della Scienza e della Tecnologia</string>
    <string name="museo_scienza_address">Via S. Vittore 21, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_scienza_desc">First opened to the public in 1953 with the Leonardo da Vinci exhibition, whom the museum was named after and inspired by, the Museo Nazionale della Scienza e della Tecnologia (National Science and Technology Museum) is the largest museum of science and technology in Italy and one of the most important in the world.\n\nThe aim of the museum is to educate and engage new audiences about scientific phenomena in a practical way and it successfully manages this through the use of interactive workshops that can be enjoyed by everyone.\n\nHousing the largest collection in the world of car models made from drawings by Leonardo da Vinci it also includes reconstructions of his famous flying machine and many of his original drawings can also be viewed.\n\nCollections are organised by the following departments: Materials, Transportation, Energy, Communication, Leonardo Arts &amp; Science, New Frontiers and Science for Children.\n\nThere is even a real submarine that you can visit (reservations to be made at the front desk – separate ticket is required) plus a number of old steam trains to climb aboard, aeroplanes and even a full-scale reconstruction of the ballroom and bridge of an ocean liner.\n\nThe main museum building with its beautiful cloisters dates back to the early 16th century when it served as a monastery for Olivetan monks.</string>
    <string name="museo_leonardo_url">http://leonardo3.net/en</string>
    <string name="museo_leonardo_name">Museo Il Mondo di Leonardo</string>
    <string name="museo_leonardo_address">Via S. Vittore 21, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_leonardo_desc">Leonardo3 – The World of Leonardo da Vinci is one of the most important events of the year. This Exhibit is not to be missed. The discovery of Leonardo da Vinci, the artist and inventor, with working models of his machines and digitalized restorations of his paintings, a worldwide first.\n\nThe Submarine, the Time Machine, the Mechanical Dragonfly, the Rapid-Fire Crossbow, the Mechanical Eagle, the digital restoration of the Last Supper and the reconstruction of musical instruments are some of the most recent innovative additions to the exhibition.\n\nWith multimedia display stations that permit hands-on interaction. In addition to the artistic works, the codices of Leonardo in virtual format are also displayed.More than 200 interactive 3D reconstructions, accessible for all ages. This is a unique event for all the family, students, tourists and anyone interested in the discovery of Leonardo da Vinci, as never before seen.\n\n
    Recognition Patronage of the Comune di Milano and Award of Excellence from the President of the Italian Republic. Leonardo3 Museum is an institutional member of ICOM (International Council of Museums).</string>
    <string name="museo_scala_url">http://www.teatroallascala.org/it/museo-teatrale/il-museo-teatrale.html</string>
    <string name="museo_scala_name">Il Museo Teatrale</string>
    <string name="museo_scala_address">Via Filodrammatici 2, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_scala_desc">In 1911 in Paris the antiquarian Sambon put up for auction a lot of highly valuable antiques relating to music and the theatre. In America the magnate John Pierpont Morgan sought to add them to his own  collection so as to create a theatre museum at the Metropolitan Opera of New York; in Italy an enterprising  group was formed, backed by the Government and Victor Emmanuel III.\n\nThe leading members of the Milanese bourgeoisie and the musical world (the duke Uberto Visconti di Modrone president of the Teatro alla Scala, Giacomo Puccini, Umberto Giordano, Arrigo  Boito,  Ettore    Modigliani, the tenor Enrico Caruso, the publishers Ricordi and Sonzogno), entered the fray and  finally won.
This first lot marked the birth of the La Scala Theatre Museum that first opened in 1913, one hundred three years ago. Over time the collection, preserved in the Museum, was enriched, and its value today is inestimable.\n\nThe exhibition space is a modern institution receiving every year 250 000 visitors, and also a welcoming home for the documents, testimonies, objects,  paintings  and  sculptures which, reunited, rekindle the ephemeral delights of the theatre. Safeguarded for a century, the old mementos come back to life, enchanting and intriguing us.\n\nThe Museum also includes the Library, founded with its present structure with the 40,000 volumes given in 1952 by Renato Simoni, author and critic of the Corriere della Sera who wanted it to be dedicated to his mother Livia, and which is continuously enriched and updated.</string>
    <string name="museo_moderna_url">http://www.gam-milano.com/en/home/</string>
    <string name="museo_moderna_name">Galleria d\'Arte Moderna Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_moderna_address">Via Palestro 16, Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_moderna_desc">Villa Belgiojoso was built based on a design by Leopold Pollack between 1790 and 1796 as the private residence of Count Lodovico Barbiano di Belgiojoso, upon returning to Milan after an important diplomatic career in Europe on behalf of Austria. Right after its completion, the Villa fell into French hands and subsequently became the home of the military governor of Milan, Gioacchino Murat, and the lavish venue for ceremonies and balls.\n\nIn 1804, the Vice President of the Italian Republic, Melzi d’Eril, purchased the Villa from the Belgiojoso heirs as a present for Napoleon. On that occasion, the Villa became known as “Villa Bonaparte.” In 1806, after hosting illustrious guests like Camillo and Paolina Borghese and Letizia Ramolino, the Emperor’s mother, the Villa became the private residence of the viceroy Eugene de Beauharnais, Napoleon’s adopted son, and his wife, princess Amalia of Baviera, who, preferring the Villa to their royal palace, commissioned lavish decorations on the upper floor.\n\nOnce all art intervention were completed, the Villa’s history went hand-in-hand with that of Milan: it was the residence of officer Heinrich von Bellegarde at the dawn of the Restoration; the site of the signing of the so-called “Pace di Milano” (document with which on August 6, 1849 the city of Milan was handed over to Austria on the part of officer Radetzky, who became the Governor General of the Lombard-Veneto kingdom and also an inhabitant of the Villa, between 1857 and 1858); home to Napoleon III. Finally, it also belonged to officer Vaillant, commander of the French army in Italy at the dawn of Italian Unification.
    \n\nAfter the Unification, the Villa was assigned to the Italian Crown and was abandoned for an extended period of time. In 1920, it became State property, and important renovation work began, transforming the historic venue into the Modern Art Gallery and inaugurated in 1921.</string>
    <string name="museo_triennale_url">http://www.triennale.org/en/design_museum/</string>
    <string name="museo_triennale_name">Triennale Design Museum</string>
    <string name="museo_triennale_address">Viale Alemagna,6 Milano</string>
    <string name="museo_triennale_desc">La Triennale di Milano is a place to hang out every day. Find books and objects at the Shop, do snack between iconic design chairs to the Caffè, relax in the garden, enjoy the panoramic restaurant Terrazza Triennale for a dinner with a view. Cross the suspended footbridge and discover the Italian design from a different point of view in the Design Museum spaces. Enjoy theater, music, dance and performing arts at the Teatro dell’Arte, La Triennale theatre.</string>
    <string name="duomo_loc">45.464323, 9.191884</string>
    <string name="sforza_loc">45.470454, 9.179472</string>
    <string name="galleria_loc">45.465812, 9.189974</string>
    <string name="scala_loc">45.467550, 9.189566</string>
    <string name="arco_loc">45.475685, 9.172430</string>
    <string name="aulenti_loc">45.483530, 9.189417</string>
    <string name="grazie_loc">45.465940, 9.171348</string>
    <string name="cimitero_loc">45.487220, 9.178302</string>
    <string name="sansiro_loc">45.478089, 9.124043</string>
    <string name="bosco_loc">45.485737, 9.190597</string>
    <string name="pinacoteca_brera_loc">45.471924, 9.188297</string>
    <string name="museo_duomo_loc">45.463525, 9.191530</string>
    <string name="museo_novecento_loc">45.463442, 9.190349</string>
    <string name="museo_castello_loc">45.469566, 9.179064</string>
    <string name="museo_armani_loc">45.451524, 9.164971</string>
    <string name="museo_scienza_loc">45.462930, 9.170733</string>
    <string name="museo_leonardo_loc">45.466512, 9.189888</string>
    <string name="museo_scala_loc">45.467234, 9.189180</string>
    <string name="museo_moderna_loc">45.472462, 9.200186</string>
    <string name="museo_triennale_loc">45.472353, 9.173957</string>
    <string name="ribot_loc">45.483205, 9.138397</string>
    <string name="rebelot_loc">45.451055, 9.172333</string>
    <string name="ratana_loc">45.485263, 9.192925</string>
    <string name="drymilano_loc">45.477756, 9.199584</string>
    <string name="joia_loc">45.477133, 9.202005</string>
    <string name="cracco_loc">45.463949, 9.187521</string>
    <string name="posto_loc">45.451214, 9.211741</string>
    <string name="mangiari_loc">45.443704, 9.117754</string>
    <string name="berbere_loc">45.487393, 9.190978</string>
    <string name="brisa_loc">45.465223, 9.180604</string>
    <string name="name_var">placeName</string>
    <string name="address_var">placeAddress</string>
    <string name="desc_var">placeDescription</string>
    <string name="img_var">placeImage</string>
    <string name="audio_var">placeAudio</string>
    <string name="site_var">placeSite</string>
    <string name="loc_var">placeLocation</string>
    <string name="coffee">Coffee</string>
    <string name="marotin_name">Marotin</string>
    <string name="marotin_address">Via Archimede 59, Milano</string>
    <string name="marotin_desc">For the best apple cake in town, don’t miss this darling little corner spot in a quiet, residential area behind Via Lincoln. Reminiscent of a patisserie you would find in the backstreets of the Marais, Marotin’s gorgeous pastel hues will lure you in, and their equally delicious cappuccinos and croissants, plus the charming Art Nouveau floors and chic floaty design touches, will keep you coming back for more. It’s beautiful here.</string>
    <string name="marotin_url">https://www.tripadvisor.co.hu/Restaurant_Review-g187849-d6210581-Reviews-Marotin-Milan_Lombardy.html</string>
    <string name="marotin_loc">45.465601, 9.213652</string>
    <string name="como_name">10 Corso Como</string>
    <string name="como_address">Corso Como, 10, Milano</string>
    <string name="como_desc">It’s hard to ignore the beauty and magic of the courtyard cafe here at 10 Corso Como. A mainstay on the fashion and design circuit in Milano, this romantic spot is surrounded by a world of citrus trees. It’s the most idyllic spot to sip on good coffee and tea after pounding the cobblestoned streets and shopping up a storm in the boutique next door. This is an afternoon worth looking forward to.</string>
    <string name="como_url">http://www.10corsocomo.com/</string>
    <string name="como_loc">45.481965, 9.187687</string>
    <string name="gattullo_name">Pasticceria Gattullo</string>
    <string name="gattullo_address">Piazzale di Porta Lodovica, 2, Milano</string>
    <string name="gattullo_desc">For something more traditional there’s no missing Gattullo. We love this spot. Considered by many locals as a stalwart for all things delicious, this pastry shop and bakery has been a Milanese institution since 1961. Come here for excellent coffee (best enjoyed standing at the bar) and a tasty assortment of homemade brioches, pastries, panettone, bigne, cannoli, and rum-soaked baba. The décor is old-school Italy (think colourful, somewhat gaudy, and totally over the top). The uniforms match. It is full of charm, and there’s an energy here that is undeniably Milanese. It’s not only great for coffee, but it’s also the perfect answer for your picnic needs – the sandwiches to-go are worth waiting for.</string>
    <string name="gattullo_url">http://www.gattullo.it/</string>
    <string name="gattullo_loc">45.452082, 9.185875</string>
    <string name="sissi_name">Pasticceria Sissi</string>
    <string name="sissi_address">Piazza Risorgimento 6, Milano</string>
    <string name="sissi_desc">Stepping into this enchanting pasticceria tucked down a side street on Piazza Risorgimento is somewhat like walking into a Wes Anderson film. Vintage paintings adorn the pink-coloured walls of this colourful tearoom and the friendly French-speaking staff swan around in a handsome uniform of caps and aprons. The coffee is (obviously) delicious and there is a super romantic ivy-covered garden courtyard where you can enjoy it. Known for having some of the best croissants in town, Sissi’s homemade cakes, cannoli and breakfast brioche will also have you coming back for more. This is a friendly neighbourhood spot where the staff will remember you by name, and you’ll likely be rubbing shoulders with the who’s who of the fashion set, who work nearby. Place your order at the bar, eat, drink and then pay. And keep in mind, they’re closed on Tuesdays (completely devastating if you forget, trust us).</string>
    <string name="sissi_url">https://www.tripadvisor.it/Restaurant_Review-g187849-d2695674-Reviews-Pasticceria_Sissi-Milan_Lombardy.html</string>
    <string name="sissi_loc">45.467173, 9.209956</string>
    <string name="cuccagna_name">Cascina Cuccagna</string>
    <string name="cuccagna_address">Via Giuseppe Ponzio, 82, Milano</string>
    <string name="cuccagna_desc">It’s hard to believe that you could drink good coffee and enjoy lunch on a farm in the centre of Milano, but at Cascina Cuccagna this is exactly what you can do. Immersed amongst the tall apartment buildings of the Porto Romana neighbourhood, this formerly abandoned 17th-century farmhouse was recently converted into an urban farm, cultural centre and café. It’s a peaceful and relaxing oasis amid the hustle and bustle of the city. The coffee is good, the Campari is even better and there are plenty of beautiful outdoor green spaces to enjoy it. With a rotating,seasonal menu, the food options here are wonderful as well.</string>
    <string name="cuccagna_url">http://www.cuccagna.org/portal/IT/handle/?page=homepage</string>
    <string name="cuccagna_loc">45.482332, 9.230543</string>
    <string name="pave_name">Pavé Milano</string>
    <string name="pave_address">Via Felice Casati 27, Milano</string>
    <string name="pave_desc">An artisan bakery where everything is made in front of your eyes. A world of food, music and words where making good products and bring them to you in the most beautiful way possible. Quality ingredients, traditional values and craftsmanship are all implemented in our small kitchen laboratory. And a window on everyday world is there to share our lives with you. There will be times when the fragrance of our breads will blend with the aroma of the cakes, your words will translate into songs and your smiles will become our favourite good morning.</string>
    <string name="pave_url">https://www.pavemilano.com/en/</string>
    <string name="pave_loc">45.479110, 9.202548</string>
    <string name="cat_name">Crazy Cat Cafe</string>
    <string name="cat_address">Via Napo Torriani 5, Milano</string>
    <string name="cat_desc">The Crazy Cat Café came about because of a great love for cats and thanks to an unforgettable experience in Japan, in a Neko Café in Osaka. So, in October 2015, the one and only first Cat Café in Lombardy was opened. Its aim, following the Italian lifestyle, is to offer an intimate meeting place like the typical Japanese Neko Cafés, where the real hosts are the nine cats living in the Café.</string>
    <string name="cat_url">http://www.crazycatcafe.it/en/</string>
    <string name="cat_loc">45.480876, 9.203487</string>
    <string name="bianco_name">Bianco Latte</string>
    <string name="bianco_address">Via Turati 30, Milano</string>
    <string name="bianco_desc">Biancolatte offers a great variety of homemade products for breakfast: croissants, muffins, baci di dama, and many types of cookies and biscuits.</string>
    <string name="bianco_url">http://www.biancolatte.it/en</string>
    <string name="bianco_loc">45.476279, 9.195476</string>
</resources>

